I'm here at Atlas Survival Shelters with
the owner, Ron. Hey, Joe. And I've heard
they build the best doomsday vaults in
America and worldwide. What exactly do
you do here, Ron? Well, we build bomb
shelters. And we we've made our fame for
making shelters for the rich and famous.
The Kim Kardashians, Mark Zuckerbergs,
Andrew Tates, and uh Mr. Beast of the
world. We build their bunkers. I am very
interested in what you do.
>> I like your shirt now. I'm a prepper.
I'm a prepper, too, by the way. You do
make badass bunkers, right?
>> Yeah, I make badass mine. There's about
50 of them here in this factory.
>> Can we see them?
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, this is uh here,
I'll give you a quick tour here. So,
this is our our little hall of fame or
wall of fame here or a wall of shame, I
guess. Uh
Yeah?
Yeah. Bunker boom. Oh, yeah. Where's the
Bunker Babe magazine? Bunker Babe
magazine? We are working on that. It'll
be published
>> released it yet.
>> It'll be published published in the
second quarter of this year.
But, um yeah, out here
Oh, good. They just brought in more
bunkers.
>> Woah. Yeah.
So, this is a big factory
and uh
here, I'll take you over here and then
we'll go through the process of how we
make them cuz there's a bunch of welding
involved. I also, what you see here are
a lot of parts. So, if somebody's going
to build a bomb shelter for themselves
uh out of usually concrete, I supply the
doors and the air systems, the hatches,
escape doors, and everything they need
to build their own bomb shelter.
>> Concrete polymer?
Uh no, it's just it's just precast
concrete shelter. That's called our
backyard bunker. That's only a $25,000
shelter. So, that is like the working
man's shelter that anybody can afford.
We make a like a metal box here. Use
them plate steel, I-beams, and channels.
And uh Right here?
Yeah. So, this is
This is an actual bunker build.
>> Well, this is actually the generator
room for a bunker. This isn't really the
bunker. This is the generator room for a
bigger bunker. So, this will have a
diesel generator in here. See, it feels
like you're in a ship, don't it? You
come in, you go down the steps, there'll
be a diesel generator here, fuel tanks,
and uh big room. Yeah. Giant. It's
giant, yeah. Also, metal. This is EMP
proof. It is. It is. If you uh if you
prepare it and give all the uh all the
openings covered properly, it is EMP
proof.
I'm just going to say you'll have some
fantastic welders. Yeah, we do. You got
to be a good welder here cuz
everything's pressure tested, it's got
to be leak proof. That looked like a
bead of caulk, homie. Yeah. Beautiful.
Yeah. Wow.
And so, how do you build these things?
On the outside, is it steel I-beam
construction? Yeah. Yeah, I-beams on the
ceiling, I-beams on the floor, uh plate
steel on the wall, uh channels all the
way around for uh lateral support. And
then, look at these big welds right
here. All uphill welds. Wow. Yeah. So,
they're uh
they're made like a like a fuel tank,
they're tested uh for with air to make
sure they don't have any leaks, then we
weld the inside because they got to be
underground, they got to be watertight
so they don't leak.
This is fantastic. So, this is a laser
plasma cutter? It's not a plasma. Plasma
is a different type. This is strictly
laser.
Yeah. So, it's just a laser will cut it.
Wow. Yeah. It's a lot cleaner than a
plasma.
Cool.
Yeah. And then, this one here cuts uh
I-beams and square tubing.
Um
Yeah, this one will cut like tubings and
squares and whatever.
Cut all the shapes up. How much does one
of these saws cost?
Uh this is a laser saw, so they're about
a half million dollars.
>> Claim. Is it water cooled? Is it what?
Is it water cooled? Water cooled? Uh it
actually is.
Yeah, it does have a a chill system in
it. I don't know really how it works.
It's beyond my pay grade. But uh yeah,
it does a good job for cutting pipes and
whatever we're going to use it for.
What is that spaceship launch bay?
Well, that's that be the laser over
there. That's where it's cut. The
laser's in that room there. So, the
material loads in there like a bullet in
a rifle and then goes through there and
gets cut over there.
Woah.
This is fantastic.
How many of these do you make a year?
I really don't count, but
I mean, these big bunkers?
Probably a hundred something a year, the
big ones. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, tell me more about a bunker.
What all goes into them? What do you
think about? Well, I mean, they're
basically like a house underground. It's
got bedrooms and bathrooms and kitchens
and
except my bunkers have like underfloor
storage like an airplane where you put
your luggage. You got water tanks. You
got food.
But then you've got a mechanical room
with a diesel generator, a battery room,
a decontamination room, and a mudroom.
So, the living quarters just feels like
any house, but then you have all these
mechanical rooms that you know that you
know you're in a bomb shelter when
you're going through all these submarine
doors. You feel like you're going into
the the bowels of a ship, you know?
So,
>> Do you have one we can look at?
>> They're all over the place. You can pick
one out. But most of what you're seeing
right now, these are all the engine
rooms that they're building right now.
So, that you think that's a bunker, but
that's just the engine room to a bunker
cuz these bunkers I'm making right now
are big like two, three, four thousand
square feet bunkers.
Yeah. So, they have like two, three
million dollar bunkers. Will you tell me
where we go look and I'll go.
>> Well, we'll go we'll go up front because
we got more of them out here. This one
here, I think the lights on are in this
one.
>> Oh, yeah.
Yeah, this one has power.
>> Yeah.
Okay. Hold on.
My first time inside a bunker is with
Ron.
>> Okay. So,
I just closed down the door. So, we're
actually inside the bunker right now.
Ain't nobody getting in that guy. No,
well, this is really designed just to
keep the smoke out. Okay, so when this
is closed and then you tighten the nuts,
it will actually become airtight and
there won't be any daylight or smoke
that can get through there. There's also
at the surface a bulletproof hatch, so
when you go into a bunker, you got a
bulletproof hatch that will stop
anything up to a 50 cal.
Then you got to go through two of these
gas tight doors to get to the bunker.
Woah. So, once you're in the bunker,
you're sealed. You notice there's no
echo in here right now cuz of these
mattresses. Usually there's an echo in
an empty box, but it's really quiet in
here right now. But we're in just one of
the two bedrooms in this 10 by 50-ft
bunker. So, a bunker like this, if
you're curious, costs like $250,000 plus
the installation, which is probably
another 100,000 with freight. And then
you got to put in batteries and then
generators, so these are not cheap. Mhm.
It's like buying a Ferrari, okay? I'd
rather have this than a Ferrari. Well,
depends on your age, but I would, too,
you know? Ferraris they get they get
driven for 2 days, they get parked in
the garage, and then you show one or two
friends, and that's it. And this is the
air system. This is how you actually
breathe in the bunker. So, this is the
NBC air filtration system. Uh this is
electric, so you just turn it on and
leave it on, but if you were to lose
power, you can manually operate this
with a hand crank. And uh this way it
exchanges the air and it has a HEPA
filter,
has a carbon filter and another HEPA
filter, but basically pull out the
gases, uh any chemicals, or any
radiation that's supposed to be in the
air through the carbon and through the
HEPA filters and make it where you can
breathe the air. And this thing doesn't
pull hardly any energy at all.
>> No, it doesn't pull a lot of amps. I
mean, it's like
>> 180 watts. Yeah, so it's pulling The
whole bunker's pulling like 15 amps with
an air system and the lights, that's
that's it. And it shouldn't need much
heat or AC if it's underground, too.
>> No, well, no, no. When you're in a
bunker underground, it stays at like
Depends on where you're at. If you're in
Minnesota, the bunker stays 52°
in the winter and 58 in the summer, but
you come to Texas it'll be like 58 60 in
the winter and then the summer it'll get
up to like maybe 68 70 underground even
though it's 100 outside but it'll stay
cool underground. I bet you could sell a
lot of bunkers in Minnesota right now. I
I do a lot in Minnesota. And I like
these obviously these fold in and out.
Yeah, well these are folding beds. Yeah,
these just fold up.
>> This what I think? Yeah, storage. Yeah,
it's where you keep all your food
supplies down there.
>> There's your water tank. Okay. Yeah, two
water tanks.
>> water does it hold?
>> 600 gallons of water.
Plus all the food you can stuff under
the floor which is a lot. A lot. You
could put a lot of MREs under there.
Yeah, I mean a bunker like this will
hold over a year's worth of food. So the
bunker is actually made with Trex
decking for the floors. The walls are
hardy board. They're actually concrete
and then the counters are marble. Yeah,
this is in the granite.
>> So there's really nothing in here that
will um
um mold or decompose over time. So
everything in here is made to last 100
years. That's why we're using it. We
don't want the floors to be going warped
getting warped or moldy or wearing out.
So we're using stuff that has a history
of lasting forever. This would be their
their guest bedrooms possibly cuz it
it's going to be treated like a basement
that's built out.
>> These are hardwood cabinets. This
actually looks like high-end quartzite.
And let's see.
Soft close. You know I remodeled 3 years
Yeah, stainless steel sinks. Open that
up. It's got reverse osmosis down there.
Okay, so we have a water filter. Yeah,
reverse osmosis, stainless steel
microwave and of course it's got a full
bathroom. I love these little corner
ones.
Yeah,
good clean installation, good cuts. Oh.
Okay. Panel. Yeah, 520s, 115, 160, air
filtration. Everything in here seems to
be tuned to just optimum efficiency.
Everything you need and nothing you
don't. Behind this, this is the dog
house but that's also the escape tunnel
that leads to the secondary escape. And
here's your pump. This is a 120 water
pump. I see the plug right here. GFI
protected filter. That's got to be your
water heater, isn't it?
Uh the top one's a water This is your
water filter for the sediment. This is
your pump, and then this is your water
heater. This makes the water drinkable,
but we also put it through the reverse
osmosis. Reverse osmosis makes it even
better in case the water's been stored
for too long. What was your favorite
bunker you've ever built? Oh god. You
know, I mean, the bunkers that have
shooting ranges are cool, like the bank.
You can drive a car in them and stuff.
So, it's actually the bunkers I'm making
right now are the are the favorite ones,
but I'm under non-disclosure. I can't
film them. I can't photograph them. I
can't do anything. I would see why
people having doomsday bunkers would not
want them filmed and displayed.
>> So, so what I'm saying is my best work I
can't show, film, or display. Okay. I
don't want to get caught breaking a
non-disclosure with the their powerful
people. Yeah. If I spent 3 million on a
bunker, I wouldn't want nobody knowing
what the inside is. Well, this bunker is
more secret than the That's an
overpressure blast valve. That's what I
was about to say.
>> Yeah, so as the air fills up in the
bunker right here,
uh this will let the air out. So,
uh it's like a Since you turn on the air
system, this is going to open because
there's going to be more air than there
was in here before. So, it Let's say you
got 4,000 cubic feet of air when you
turn on the air system, you're
immediately going to have 4,100. So,
it's got to let some of the air out,
otherwise it wants to pop. Your your
head would be feel like it's going to
explode. So, this lets all the air out.
And if there was a blast, that would go
off, it would go like that. The blast
would close this and protect the
inhabitants. But when the air system's
running, this is your overpressure blast
valve that lets all the excess air out,
including carrying out the carbon
dioxide. Dude, that's fantastic.
>> Yeah. I like it. It's a check valve for
air. Huh. It It is a check valve for
air.
>> It's exactly what it is. Y'all have
thought about pretty much everything.
Yeah. This is a 10 by 50.
Um We make the bunkers in
four sizes, eight wide, 10 wide, as this
is, 12 wide, and 14 wide. What's your
most popular size you think?
Well, in the small bunkers, 10 by 20. In
the big bunkers, the 12 by 50, which is
called the big boy. So, 2 ft wider. This
bunker feels really big when it's 12 ft
wide. I live in a van. This feels giant.
In a Costa Rica, I have a little maybe
maybe 400 sq ft, 20 by 25. Maybe maybe
maybe about this size. But man, I would
say that this is enough for an entire
two-person family to live in, maybe
three, four. Yeah. I like this, man.
When they're decked out and they got the
rugs down and the pictures on the wall
and all the bookshelves,
I mean, it feels like sounds like just
like mini cabin or
home or Ron, what do you see what do you
see next for Atlas bunkers? Global.
We're we've expanded worldwide. So,
we've got licensed franchises coming up
in 30, 40 countries in the Asia, the
Middle East, Central America, South
Africa, all of Europe. I've got licensed
franchises all over. So, Atlas is set up
to be a global brand, kind of like a
I mean, like a McDonald's. I I did want
to tell you, you going around if you
have to talk me to build a bunker, I am
going to build these things all day
long.
>> [laughter]
>> I have been building things my entire
life and this is very impressive and I
want to thank you for taking your time
and telling me what's on your mind.
You're a very interesting guy. Okay. I'm
glad to have met you and I will Well,
thank you. Thanks for [laughter] coming
by. Yeah, and I'm going to Big Battery
to do their solar stuff. If they ever I
I use Big Battery in my bunkers. Well,
Big Battery is legit, Marshall is legit.
Thank you to Eric and Marshall at Big
Battery for setting this up and thank
you for Ron for taking your time out.
>> Anytime. Come back. This has been great
seeing the world's craziest doomsday
vault bunkers. Yeah,
awesome.